# **AKSHAY SINHA**

# **AKSHAYSIN**HA.CA

CELL: 4167050684 | EMAIL: AKSHAY92CA@GMAIL.COM | GITHUB | KAGGLE | LINKEDIN

# **PROFILE**

Motivated, teamwork-oriented, and responsible Data Analyst with experience in increasing comprehension of reports and presentations by the average professional. Highly educated, possessing Diploma in Business Administration in Finance and professional certification in Data Analysis. Bilingual in English and Hindi with intermediate understanding of Urdu and Punjabi.

# **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: 'R', SQL, Python

Libraries: tidyverse, dyplr, ggplot2, lubridate, tibble

Data Management: Database Design & Management, Data Quality Assessment, Data Analysis, Pattern & Trend

Identification, Visualization of Data Insights

Other: Tableau, HTML, CSS, Microsoft Office Suite, Google Suite

#### **PROJECTS**

Divvy Bike Share Program - Link

- Used 'R' to handle multiple large sets of data
- Cleaned, process and analyzed data frames using libraries like tidyverse, and lubridate in 'R'
- Used library ggplot2 for data visualization
- Made recommendations to the company about next steps for growth in membership

#### Covid Data Exploration - Link

- Microsoft Excel for changing file format from .xlsx to .csv
- Microsoft SQL Management Server to create SQL queries and export tables to Excel
- Excel to upload data to Tableau public
- Tableau to create dashboard visuals

# Nashville Housing Data Cleaning - Link

- Microsoft Excel for changing file format from .csv to .xlsx
- Microsoft SQL Management Server to create SQL queries to edit and split columns into more accessible columns

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Films & Commercials Various Location

DOP, Camera Operator, 1st & 2nd Camera Assistant

Mar 2018 – April 2021

- Executed concepts into scenes under short deadlines
- Managed and coached new hires on the various equipment used on a shoot
- Operated various different camera systems and lens for tv shows and commercials
- Maintained a flexible work ethic to support evolving production needs

#### **Cosmos Financial Group Inc.**

Mississauga

Administrative Assistant

June 2017 – September 2018

- Generated reports and presentations for monthly and quarterly review
- Addressed client's policy concerns through data visualization and data manipulation
- Increased policy adherence by 15% by maintaining strong communication channel with clients

Nike Corporation Scarborough

Health and Safety Specialist

Aug 2016 - Mar 2017

- Enforced safety regulations across the warehouse which cut down on accident by 37%
- Optimized vendor information catalog to ensure all vendors on the property had proper training, certificates and licenses
- Increase battery changing area capacity by 200% by implementing new schematics
- Redesigned high traffic areas to bring monthly forklift accidents from 4-5 to 0
- Created employee data sheets and pivot tables for cross checking licenses, permits and validations

Bank of Nova Scotia Mississauga

Customer Service Representative – Team Leader

Nov 2012 - July 2016

- Earned vault code privileges and directed branch cash holdings for day to day transactions
- Trained team members in day to day banking operations
- Advised customers on various financial opportunities
- · Organized shipment of incoming and outgoing cash shipments, bank drafts, money orders etc.

# **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Coursera - Online

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate 04/2021 – 07/2021

**Toronto Film School - Toronto** 

Film Production 06/2017-12/2018

Canadian Securities Institute - Toronto

Investment Funds in Canada 06/2015

Juno College - Toronto

Web Development 08/2019 – 10/2019

**Sheridan College - Oakville** 

Business Administration in Finance 01/2012-06/2016